Aku Alatao

C++, Java, SQL Developer

netragonlong@gmail.com +1 812 809 4741 Toronto, Ontario, Canada



SUMMARY

Aku is efficient, certified developer with 10 years of experience in software development.

Well-versed in C++, Java and SQL for building desktop and web application development.

Led programming and upkeep for 30+ client-server model software and windows services with 100% positive client feedback.

Respectful self-motivator gifted at finding reliable solutions for software issues.

Fluent in English and accustomed to working with cross-cultural, global teams.

With a strong attention to detail and accuracy and the important ability to function well in a team setting, He is looking for a C++, Java developer job within a forward-moving company.

EDUCATION

The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

Hong Kong | April 2009 - March 2013 Faculty of Engineering

WORK HISTORY

RevupCommerce | Team lead and Senior C++, Java Developer Orlando, Florida | May 2020 - April 2023

18+ long and short term projects / DFS, WSS, DBS, PA Crime Victims ...

- \bullet Worked on 10+ SQL database design projects and improved speed to complete projects by 35% in 15 weeks.
- Collaborated with a team of C++, Java developers to enhance and maintain for 10+ .Net services and Winforms desktop application.
- Built responsive, dynamic web app, web API utilizing ASP.NET Core MVC, SQL Server, Entity Framework, Linq, Javascript, Azure and fixed bugs.
- Experience with Azure APIM services and APIs integrated into them and hosted in the Azure cloud.
- Followed DAO Design Pattern and used Agile/Scrum development methodology for software development process.
- Developed and maintained giant client-server model system such as distributed systems, stabilization systems and data backup systems which are based on high availability methodologies (Failover, Load balancing, Fault-tolerance), and built their modernistic backend APIs and hosted them on the Namenode and the Active server.
- Achieved 100% client satisfaction and on-time completion.
- ullet Apply principles of trust, transparency, accountability and ownership.
- Dedicated team leader with the ability to effectively manage and achieve project goals, leveraging my complex understanding of systems engineering concepts.

Automated Systems Ltd | C++, C# Developer

Hong Kong | May 2014 - Feb 2020

20+ long term projects using C++, MFC, .Net / Forte 9, 10, 11, ScanScore, FortePlayer

- Built 30+ .Net Services and developed Winforms admin pages to manage 7M Amazon Products automatically for purchasing and sales and resulted in over \$155k in annual savings.
- Designed and developed the Chinese TianShen notation feature in 3+ Forte projects and grew revenue by 200% in first 11 months (representing 40% of company revenue).

- Improved efficiency on 5+ Forte sub projects speeding up project completion by 20%.
- Increased client satisfaction from 84% to 97% in 2016 and awarded employee of the Month twice for performing great work.
- Troubleshot and fixed any threads and bugs, communicated with clients to provide knowledge, expertise, and support, ensuring that their requirements were fully met.
- Completed analysis, design and testing phases of software development life cycle.
- Researched and integrated design strategies, product specifications, development schedules and user expectations into product capabilities.

FunctionEight | Passionate C++/MFC Intern, Junior developer

Hong Kong | Feb 2013 - Apr 2014

- 5+ long term projects / Mail Magic Professional, Ez-Architect
- Built 5 customer-facing small windows applications which increased sales by 55%.
- Redesigned and developed Mail delivery and 2d-architecture design project and added new features to meet customer's needs.
- Troubleshot and resolved performance issues for mysql and sql server databases and software.
- Analyzed, evaluated and developed new web and database applications.

SKILLS

Libraries/Frameworks: Spring Boot, Hibernate, JSF, GWT, .Net Framework, .Net Core, ASP.NET, ASP.NET Core, MVC API, Winforms, MFC, Entity Framework,

Ling, Unit Testing Framework, T-SQL, Telerik, DevExpress, Qt,

Gin,

Tools / Platforms: SSIS, SSRS, IIS, CI/CD, Azure, Scrum/Agile methodologies

Databases: MS SQL Server, Oracle, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Neo4J, Redis
Other: Linux/Unix, Socket Programming, Backend Programming, Object

Oriented Programming

CERTIFICATIONS

• SQL (Advanced) Certificate | HackerRank

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/6901fbe57eb2

CONTACT ME

Telegram: https://t.me/netragonlong
Skype: live:.cid.1bf088802735c54a
Github: https://github.com/alleycat1

Linkedin: https://linkedin.com/in/aku-alatao-352175278